Haleigh Dalke

New York, NY 11211 | 408-722-8871 | haleighdalke@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

JOB TITLE

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in visual and performing arts. Possess strong skills in analytical thinking and collaboration that help independent teams deliver a polished, thoughtful product. Thrives when linking creativity, technicality, and formality to communicate meaningful project missions and execute efficient code. Excited about providing solutions for a more inclusive and sustainable economy.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, MySQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

restage - Github | Demo

Full stack video streaming application for professional dance on camera

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Integrated the YouTube API to curate playlists and perform CRUD on videos
- Enhanced design and frontend interface with Reactstrap and custom CSS

fit-task-ic - Github | Demo

Collaborative full stack habit tracking application

- Implemented data visualization with Chart.js to animate a user's goals and progress
- Strategized project functionality with wireframes and model outlines to optimize organization and efficiency
- Followed RESTful routes and applied React router to properly distribute backend/frontend responsibility

Jokebox - Github | Demo

Simple CLI application using Rails that allows a user to interact with silly jokes

- Established model relationships, utilizing conventional naming practices for optimal ActiveRecord functionality
- Defensively programmed against improper user input to prevent application breakage
- Maintained single responsibility principle and followed "DRY" practices to promote reusability and easy debugging

EXPERIENCE

Lincoln Center, Radio City Music Hall

Professional Dancer

New York, NY 09/2017 - 06/2020

Performed locally and internationally with various recognized dance companies, including Trisha Brown and Kidd Pivot

New York University

New York, NY

Tutor: Intro to CompSci, Database Design

09/2016 - 05/2017

- Mentored undergraduate students in the fundamentals of Java, Python, SQL, PHP, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS
- Examined lessons and refined using relatable, easy-to-understand language and metaphorical examples
- Solved code errors by quickly identifying bugs, listening to the student's thought processes, and carefully comparing and contrasting with the correct solution for enhanced comprehension

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

San Francisco, CA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

06/2020 - 09/2020

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) in Dance, Minor in Web Applications and Computer Programming GPA 3.8

08/2014 - 05/2017

GPA 3.8